Ananya Agarwal

+91 9634215260

☑ ananya.agr18@gmail.com

Noida

Ø ananya1898.github.io

in ananya-agarwal-1555201b6

nanya1898

Summary _

Automation test engineer experienced in software development processes and optimal testing strategies. Helps teams produce exceptional products by offering in-depth quality assurance support. Open and clear communicator with good multitasking skills, organised nature, and strong attention to detail.

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics And Communication

2017 - 2021

• Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida

• CGPA: 8.2

Delhi Public School

2012 - 2016

• Senior Secondary School, CGPA: 8.3 (2014-2016)

• Secondary School, CGPA: 10 (2012-2014)

Experience _

Ion Group, Automation Analyst

Noida, India Aug. 2021 - Present

- Demonstrated expertise as the sole leader in automating testing procedures for legacy software and infrastructure components, ensuring the high-quality deliverables for leading banks like UBS, Scotia, Mitsubishi, and Pierpont.
- Successfully progressed from a graduate role to spearheading the Quality Assurance team, showcasing leadership and proficiency in automation testing over the past 3 years.
- Spearheaded efforts to reduce the monthly testing cycle work by 50% to an efficient automated process, showcasing commitment to optimizing workflows.
- Accelerated issue resolution by fostering effective collaboration with developers during root cause analysis investigations.

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Program Analyst Trainee

India

- Developed strong problem-solving skills by troubleshooting complex issues during the internship period.
- Gained valuable experience working within an agile development environment, utilizing Scrum methodologies.

Feb. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Projects _____

- Filtering and Detection of Hoax news using Machine Learning
- Triple Threshold Statistical Detection filter for removing high density random-valued impulse noise in images using Python.

Skills

Python, Git, SQL, Bash, RobotFrameWork, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Jira, Scrum, Agile

Interests

Swimming, Playing Guitar, Travelling, Feeding and Caring for Stray Dogs, Reading